Web Development

Expert programmer in languages such as Ruby, HTML5/XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Perl, SQL, JSP, and Unix Shell. My coding experience also includes Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Prototype, Haml, Sass, CoffeeScript, RSpec, Shoulda, Test::Unit, Cucumer, Script.aculo.us, Mootools, Zend Framework and Wordpress templates and plug-ins. I am well versed in Unix/Linux system administration and Apache, MySQL, and SSH management. My software experience includes Adobe Photoshop, Flash, and InDesign; Apple OS X, Linux/BSD. Microsoft Windows 9x/XP/Vista operating systems; Vi, Text-Mate, Subversion and Git. My written and verbal skills are excellent.

I build to web standards and properly support Firefox 3+, Google Chrome, Safari, Mobile Safari and Internet Explorer 6+.

EXPERIENCE

Incapsulate

Ruby Developer, Washington, DC

April 2010 - Present

Incapsulate a high-end IT consulting firm providing commercial and government solutions. As a Ruby Developer I am responsible for:

- Front-end development, HTML5/XHTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery
- Back-end development, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL
- Server Administration

Ready Labs (previously Six Studios, LLC)

Freelance Web Development, Falls Church, VA

May 2008 - Present

Six Studios is my freelance business through which I offer web-based solutions to small businesses. From its inception I have provided:

- Website development, XHTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript
- Custom content management systems, Ruby on Rails, PHP, SQL, JavaScript

- Social Media integration
- Dedicated Unix server management

The average freelance project consists of strategy, programming, testing, deployment, and maintenance.

Content Management Systems grant the business the ability to update their website. Clients have different needs. Because of this, I created a lightweight, flexible CMS to fit the requirements of each client.

Greenfield/Belser Ltd.

Lead Developer & Linux System Administrator, Washington, DC March 2005 - 2010
Greenfield/Belser is not only one of the largest design firms in the DC/metro area they are also responsible for the nutrition facts label found on billions of food products nationwide. As lead developer and Linux system administrator at Greenfield/Belser I am responsible for:

- Ongoing development of the studio's content management system, PHP, Ruby on Rails, XHTML, CSS, JavaScript
- · Building client websites and web solutions, PHP, XHTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Researching latest technologies and industry changes
- Developing tools for task automation, Ruby on Rails, XHTML
- Training the team of coding standards and practices
- Improving on existing programming methods and code libraries
- Deploying and maintaining multiple Linux servers

Dandy Connections, Inc

Web Developer & Junior System Administrator, Atlantic City, NJ

August 2001 - 2004

Dandy Connections, Inc. is a nationwide Internet Service Provider. While employed at Dandy Connections I was responsible for aiding the System Administrator in maintenance of multiple web, mail, and database servers. I was also tasked with developing web-based server automation tools in Perl producing and client websites in PHP and Flash.

Further responsibilities included providing technical assistance to clients with dial-up, network, and DSL issues.

EDUCATION

Northern Virginia Community College

Mathematics & Sciences, Sterling, VA

September 2004

Calculus, Chemistry, and Biology.

Additional schooling includes: Physics and video editing

CONTACT

Dane Harrigan

Email: dane.harrigan@gmail.com

Phone: 202-674-2122

Website: http://codequietly.com

Twitter: http://twitter.com/daneharrigan